Finding Aid for Booker T. Washington Business Association records, 1941-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Booker T. Washington Business Association records 1941-1999 1968-1971
Booker T. Washington Business Association.
1.5 linear feet
9995 Bc 2
Organization of Detroit African American business and professional men and women; scattered records of the organization including newsletters, directories, and topical files of some of the group’s presidents.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the organization (donor no. 8956 ) in 1999-2000. Some published material came from Wardell Croft (donor no. 8895 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Booker T. Washington Business Association was organized in 1930 by a small group of Detroit business and professional men headed by William H. Peck. The original name of the organization was the Booker T. Washington Trade Association. One of the purposes of the organization was to promote the development of local businesses.
The record group has been arranged into four series: Background/Informational; President's Files; National Business League, and Wallace Williams File. Included are scattered business and membership directories, newsletters, and annual meeting programs; records of organization presidents Homer D. Waterman, Joseph W. Williams, and Wallace Williams; and files relating to its relations with the National Business League, 1968-1970.
Subjects:
African American businesspeople--Michigan--Detroit.; African Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; African American business enterprises--Michigan--Detroit.; Booker T. Washington Business Association.; Detroit (Mich.)--Commerce.; Booker T. Washington Trade Association.; National Business League (U.S.)
Contributors:
Williams, Joseph W.; Williams, Wallace C., 1921-; Waterman, Homer D.
- Background/Informational
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1984-1991 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Banquet programs (Box 1)
  - "Guide to Better Service" business directories, 1962-1985 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous published materials (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous directories (Box 1)
- President's Files
  - Homer D. Waterman, 1968-1969
    - Business Service Committee, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Fund, University of Michigan, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Joseph W. Williams, 1970-1971
    - Activity Reports, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Black-Polish Conference, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Business protection, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Business Service Committee (Box 2)
    - Chairman of the Board (Homer Waterman) (Box 2)
    - Clippings (Box 2)
    - Committee chairmen (Box 2)
    - Committees (Box 2)
    - Community Service Committee (Box 2)
    - Ellis (Jackie Ray) extradition (Box 2)
    - Imperial Shirt, Inc. (Box 2)
    - Membership, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
    - Minority Caucus meeting (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - New Detroit, Inc., 1971 (Box 2)
    - Newsletter material (Box 2)
    - Office correspondence, 1970-1971, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Rogers (Hank) obituary; also papers re Urban Design Development Group (Box 2)
    - Women in Community Service (Box 2)
    - Women's Day Program (Box 2)
  - Wallace Williams, 1985-1986
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- National Business League
  - Project Outreach
    - Progress Report, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Activity Reports, 1970, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Project Director (R. Conrad Vaughn) file, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Convention file, Detroit, 1970, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Clippings (Box 2)
  - Publicity (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Wallace Williams File, 1991-1999
  - Scattered minutes, mailings, etc. (Box 2)